Inventory of the Archibald Woods Papers 1777-1893, 1783-1846
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- R. Berkshire, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[iba]ld Woods, near Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 12 July 1821., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1256)
  Offers to sell his house, lot and farm to Woods.
- John Bowland, Bloomington, [Indiana], to [Archibald Woods], 24 July 1821., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1257)
  [?] Buchanan is waiting Woods' reply about selling land.
- Nathan Davis, n.p., to Richard Simms, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 25 July 1821., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1258)
  Has examined land records concerning heirs of Moses Chapline.
- John & Ch[arle]s White, n.p., to Archibald Woods, near Wheeling, Virginia, August 1821., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1259)
  Charles White has written to Raccoon Mills to pay taxes on Woods' land. Asks Woods to pay amount due to John White.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to John Good, n.p., 15 August 1821., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1260)
  If Good will hire his bellows out to [Joseph] Hanlin [Handlon], Woods will see they are taken care of.
  Includes, DS of Joseph Handlon (witnessed by Andrew Donaldson) acknowledging receipt of the bellows. 1 page.
- John Stipp, Jefferson [County, West Virginia], to Archibald Wood[s], Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 20 August 1821., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1261)
  Needs a reply from Woods.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 23 August 1821., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1262)
  Col. Berkshire will write Woods. Wilson describes the house Berkshire has for sale in Morgantown and other houses available in the town.
- James Huftman, Mead Township, Belmont [Coun]ty, Ohio, to Archall [Archibald] Woods, near Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 1 September 1821., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1263)
  Has collected money owed to Woods by Asher Jones.
- Dan[ie]l [Peck?], n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., 3 September 1821., 4 pages. ALS. (Folder 1264)
  Gives Woods legal advice on a landlord collecting from a tenant.
- Joseph Spencer, Woods County, [West Virginia?], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 15 September 1821., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1265)
  Asks Woods for patents to land. Woods has had money for the land for 25 years.
- John Coll, Woodsfield [Ohio], to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 19 September 1821., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1266)
  Does not think house will suit the land or her business. Commission wants to tear it down. Mrs. Jackson has quit housekeeping.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to Moses Shepherd, n.p., 24 September 1821., 3 pages. Draft of ALS. (Folder 1267)
  Concerns a dispute between Woods and Shepherd over Woods asking for security for a loan. Woods rehearses various incidents involving the building of the National Road.
  Includes draft of ALS, of Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to Moses Shepherd, n.p., 24 September 1821, concerning a dispute between Woods and Shepherd. 3 pages.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 1 November 1821., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1268)
  Suggestions about a possible suit against [?] Booth. Wilson wedding with Woods' daughter, Mary, is set for December 6. N. Evans can not yet tell if he will sell house. [?] Stealey may be interested in exchanging property with Woods. Stealey's landed property is bound so he cannot sell or exchange it.
  Includes, ALS, or Eug[enui]s M. Wilson, [Morgantown, Virginia] [West Virginia], to Anne [(Poage)] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia]. Knows she will miss her daughter, but hope she will not delay the wedding. 1 page.
- John McCoy, "Mounthill", Tyler County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 12 November 1821., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1269)
  Agrees with Woods that honest, independent men should be appointed to Board of Directors of North West bank of Wheeling.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to Benj[ami]n Wilson, n.p., 28 November 1821., 1 page. ANS. (Folder 1269A)
  Deliver pork to Jasper Mallory.
- Dan[ie]l [Peck?], n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 29 November 1821., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1270)
  Has paid taxes for Woods.
- Henry C. Lewis, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], to [Archibald] Woods, n.p., 1 December 1821., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1271)
  Wants to settle in Indiana and found a newspaper. Needs information from Woods on likely places to settle.
- J. Holister, Woodsfield, [Ohio], to Archibal[d] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 6 December 1821., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1272)
  Wants to buy a house and lot from Woods.
- Josias Thompson, Tridelphia, to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., 8 December 1821., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1273)
  Asks Woods' help in settling accounts with [Moses] Shepherd [concerning the building of the National Road].
- Rob[er]t Woods, n.p., to Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., 25 December 1821., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1274)
  Thinks they need to obtain advice of [Philip] Doddridge.
- James Shannon, Richmond, Virginia, to Ar[c]h[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 27 December 1821., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1275)
  Archibald Woods, William Chapline and Peter Yarnall have been continued as directors in Northwest Bank of Virginia Board of Public Works are determined to coerce payment of state dividend due from North West Bank.
- Mary (Woods) Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Ann [(Poage)] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 27 December 1821., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1276)
  Discusses trip and social events in Morgantown.
- Geo[rge] Paull, St. Clairsville, [Ohio], to Ar[chibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 31 December 1821., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1277)
  Congress has asked for commissioners to file report in [Moses] Shepherd "buisiness" [sic] [Shepherd's accounts with the U.S. in the building of the National Road.]
- Jos[eph] Woods,"Westwood" [near Nashville, Tennessee], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 2 January 1822., 4 pages. ALS. (Folder 1278)
  Is enjoying life in the country. Gives disadvantages of Wheeling over Pittsburgh for trade. Involved in building the steamboat, "Nashville of Tennessee." Still owes debts in Kentucky of $2l,4000. Gives news of Woods family in Missouri, Kentucky and Virginia.
- Thomas Wheeler, Was[h]ington County, Pennsylvania, to Archabild [Archibald] Woods, near Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 8 January 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1279)
  Wants to rent for only one year.
- Jasper Mallory, Captina [Creek, Ohio], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 16 January 1822., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1280)
  Outlines a dispute with Isaac Jones.
- John Hinthorn, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., 19 January 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1281)
  Has received Woods' letter and expects to agree to the propositions.
- Cleaburn Simms, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., 20 January 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1282)
  Discusses terms of a land deal.
- Forsyth[e] Curtis, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Archibald Woods, n.p., 23 January 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1283)
  Asks Woods to give bearer, J. P. Seaman, two barrels of flour. Will be credited to Woods' subscription to the Presb[yteria]n meetinghouse.
- Isaac Jones, Captee[na] [Captina Creek, Ohio], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 26 January 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1284)
  Gives terms on which he will rent land from Woods.
- J.[?] Williams, Tyler County, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, n.p., 28 Janery [January] 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1285)
  Statement requested by John Nichols of what Samuels & Burckhaud had said respecting yours & his business.
- Cha[rle]s P. Wells, Tyler County, [Virginia], to [Archibald Woods, n.p.], 29 January 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1286)
  Wells gives his statement concerning business between John Nichols and Woods.
- D.B. Spencer, Parkers[bur]g, Virginia [West Virginia] to Archibald Woods, Wellsburgh, [Wheeling?] Virginia [West Virginia], 29 January 1822., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1287)
  Does not think Jno Wilson will bring suit. Needs copies of agreement regarding the compromise of a lawsuit.
- Archi[bal]d Wood[s], n.p., to D. B. Spencer, n.p. 2 February 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1287A)
  Declines complying with Spencer's request.
- Jasper Mallory, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, near Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 2 February 1822., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1288)
  Rehearses his dispute with [Isaac] Jones.
- Mikel Enlows, Belmont County, Ohio, to Archy [Archibald] Woods, 15 February [1822?]., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1289)
  Would like to live on Woods' land another year.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 21 February 1822., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1290)
  Housing alternatives in Morgantown.
- John Coll, Woodsfield, [Ohio], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 4 March 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1291)
  Has moved into house formerly occupied by Wido[w] Jackson. Has gone in partnership with [?] Gray in the tavern.
- Benj[ami]n Cole, n.p., to Archibald Woods, near Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 6 March 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1292)
  Asks Woods to get [paints?]
- Thomas Smith, Captina [Creek, Ohio], to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheling, [Wheeling] Virginia [West Virginia], 6 March 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1293)
  Corn is put up. Other farm business is tended to. Asks if Franklin Woods is going down the river.
- Ja[me]s Wood, Marietta, [Ohio], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 9 March 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1294)
  How and when money for public land is due.
- Jos[eph] Gadd, A. N. C., Woodsfield, [Ohio], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 9 March 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1295)
  Notifies Woods his house must be moved.
- John Coll, Woodsfield, [Ohio], to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 18 March 1822., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1296)
  Surprised Woods will not advance liquor for the tavern Coll and Gray want to establish in a building by Woods.
- Ja[me]s Pindall, Clarksburg, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 26 March 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1297)
  Bill for two land suits he is handling for Woods have not been paid.
- John Wilson, Jr., Clarksburg, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 29 March 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1298)
  Asks if a suit should be brought.
- John Coll, Woodsfield, [Ohio], to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 4 April 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1299)
  Asking for liquor for his tavern.
- James Smith, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 5 April 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1300)
  His conveyance of land to Woods omits lifting an obligation to [?] Cole. Cannot meet a proposal of Woods concerning flour and whiskey.
- James Smith, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 2 April 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1301)
  Misunderstood agreement with Woods.
- A. Samuels, Middlebourne, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Archi[bald] Woods, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 30 April 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1302)
  Recollection of a settlement of lawsuits against [?] Nichols.
- Rob[er]t Woods, n.p., to Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., 10 May 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1303)
  Asks Woods to survey some land.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to Joseph Woods, [May 1822]., 1 page. ACyS of ALs. (Folder 1304)
  Register of the land Office, Marietta, [Ohio]. Asks Woods to send patent for land. Asks about a forthcoming sale.
- Geo[rge] [Vermums?] to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., 6 May 1822., 1 page. ANS. (Folder 1304A)
  Request to let W[illia]m Clark have two barrels of flour out of Woods' subscription to the meeting house.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia, 4 June 1822., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1305)
  Encloses receipt for [James] Pindall's fees. Wilson's suit against Booth will be lengthy. Still finishing his house. [Philip] Doddridge is candidate for Congress. Extreme politeness shown Wilson family by Edward Brake [?] Jackson.
- Jesse Hunt, Cincinnati, [Ohio], to Archibald Wood[s], Near Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 8 June 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1306)
  As executor of [Jeremiah?] Hunt, he cannot exchange his brother's land, but can sell it.
- D. O. Conner, Woodsfield, [Ohio], to A[r]ch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], [15 June] 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1307)
  Does not wish to buy Woods' house.
- William Mason, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., 15 June 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1308)
  Wants use of a lot.
- John Bowland, Bloomington, Indiana, to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia, [West Virginia], 25 June 1822., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1309)
  Thinks [?] Meadows will buy land, if not, [?J Buchanan will. Gives report on crops and prices. Describes hailstorm with stones measuring fourteen inches in circumference.
- Geo[rge] Paull, St. Clairsville, [Ohio], to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., 13 July 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1310)
  Will set out for Indiana. James Paull has a bond on agents of the Penetentiary at Frankfort.
- Jesse Hunt, Cincinnati, [Ohio], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 19 July 1822., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1311)
  Offers to divide and sell brother's estate's land.
- Nathan Hanes, n.p., to Arche [Archibald] Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 21 July 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1312)
  Estimates cost of thirteen hundred dollars to build a house for Woods.
- Mary [(Woods)] Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Mrs. Ann [(Poage)] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 29 July 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1313)
  Eug[eniu]s has had fever. House is not finished yet.
- F[ranklin] Woods, Natchez, [Mississippi], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 29 July 1822., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1314)
  On his way to [New] Orleans. Gives prices.
- John Davenport, n.p., to Archibald Woods, near Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 9 August 1822., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1315)
  Has given information to [?] Chesbrough. Recommends Chesbrough as a tenant.
- John Bowland, Bloomington, Indiana, to Arch[ib]a[l]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 13 August 1822., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1316)
  Sold Woods' land to James Buckhanon. Gives news of his family.
- Invitation from Lau[?] A. & Mary D. Washington, Hills, [Ohio County, Virginia] [West Virginia] to [Archibald & Ann (Poage)] Woods for dinner, 16 August 1822., 1 page. M. (Folder 1317)
- John Bowland, Washington County, [Pennsylvania], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 21 August 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1318)
  Wants to know if Woods would exchange land in Ohio, for land in Indiana for Bowland's brother, Matthew.
- John Eaton, Morristown [?], to Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., 23 August 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1319)
  Concerns property lines and rye.
- [?] Dugan, Zanesville [Ohio], to Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 25 August 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1320)
  Appreciates Woods' offer regarding his house in Wheeling, but his wife is unwilling to reenter tavernkeeping.
- Memorandum of Franklin Woods 29 August 1822., 1 page. AMS. (Folder 1321)
  Saying that he shipped himself on board the brig "Harriot" for Baltimore with paid passage & thirteen hundred & thirty dollars.
- James Smith, Racoon Mills Park[e]r County, Indiana, to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 1 September 1822., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1322)
  Illness of everyone, Wants more land.
- J. M. Chesbrough, Baltimore, [Maryland], to Archibal[d] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], September 1822., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1323)
  Cannot keep tavern because wife is ill. Recommends John Isett.
- Lau[?] A. & Mary D. Washington, "Hills", [Ohio County, Virginia?] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 9 September 1822., 1 page. ANS. (Folder 1324)
  Would like to visit the next day.
- George Poage, Ripley, [Ohio], to Archable [Archibald] Woods, Wheeling, Vir[gini]a, [West Virginia], 16 September 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1325)
  Brother Rob[er]t Poage got ankle dislocated. Has not heard anything respecting Mr. Jening's recent [receipt?]
- Benj[amin] W. Wilson, n.p., to Archable [Archibald] Woods, n.p., 16 September 1822., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1326)
  Concerns a legal dispute. Will come in about October 5 or 6. concerns other collections.
- W. Bounds, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., 21 September 1822., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1327)
  Will write a lawyer he knows in Kentucky to get information for Woods.
- W. B. Hamilton, Philadelphia [Pennsylvania], to Archibald Wood[s], Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 24 September 1822., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1328)
  Describes death of Franklin Woods on board brig "Harriott". Woods' money, watch, and trunk are in possession of Capt. Diamond in Baltimore.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 30 September 1822?, 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1329)
  Concerns taking of depositions of Philip Doddridge, [Thomas] Wilson and [?] Hammond. "I am of your opinion that the cause ought to be tried while Judge Tucker is on the Bench. I like his bold strait-forward way of getting at justice." [Thomas Wilson's] health is not good. His [E. W.] wife and child went out in carriage.
- E. C. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 2 October 1822. (Folder 1330)
  Encloses a short address and petition relative to removal of the Seat of Government.
- Geo[rge] Pannell, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Creek [Ohio County, Virginia], 4 October 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1331)
  Supervision of cleaning out of street. Expresses sympathy in loss of Woods' son.
- Receipt for James Buckhannon's note which John Bowland is to collect. Signed by Bowland, 29 October 1822., 1 page. DS. (Folder 1332)
- J. [?] Edmondson, Louisville, [Kentucky], to Archibald Woods, near Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 14 November 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1333)
  Asks Woods for a description of his house in Wheeling.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 16 November 1822., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1334)
  Judgment has been obtained in case of Paul's ass[ign]ee vs. Boothe. Mary is in as good health as could be expected from her "delicate situation." Does not think he will move to Wheeling.
- Geo[rge] Paull, St. Clairsville, [Ohio], to A[rchibal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 14 November 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1335)
  Gives legal advice from [?] Hammond concerning the building of a house.
- John Coll, Woodsfield, [Ohio], to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 19 November 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1336)
  Has discussed deal with [?]. Minor Coll will take the bargain under certain arrangements.
- David Person, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Archibald Woods, n.p., 21 November 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1337)
  Asks Woods to deliver to Woods, Paull & Co. the bonds of Joseph Vanmeter as security.
- A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., to Eugenius Wilson, Morgantown, Virginia [West Virginia], 22 November 1822., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1338)
  Recounts death of Franklin Woods. Gives statement of Barr Wilson in lawsuit of Wilson against Daniel Booth.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to Moses Shepherd, n.p., 22 November 1822., 2 pages. ACyS of ALS. (Folder 1339)
  Goes over his side of an argument with Shepherd apparently concerning Shepherd's business with the North West Bank.
- William Madden, Washington County, Pennsylvania, to Archabal [Archibald] Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 23 November 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1340)
  Will take Woods' property if Woods will put house in order.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p,, to Will[ia]m Croghan, Jr., n.p., 26 November 1822., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1341)
  Has tended to paying Croghan's land taxes. Gives his terms for exchange of land.
- David Person, Clemington, [?], to A[rchibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 28 November 1822., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1341A)
  Recommends [?] Gray.
- Alpheus P. Willson, Richmond, [Virginia], to Tho[ma]s Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 10 December 1822., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1342)
  James Pleasants elected governor. W[illia]m Brown of Williamsburg was elected chancellor of Fredericksburgh [sic] of Williamsburg [sic] Districts. Mentions possibility of removal of seat of justice in [Ohio County, Virginia].
- Alpheus P. Willson, Richmond, [Virginia], to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 26 December 1822., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1342A)
  Bill appointing commissioners to locate seat of justice in Ohio County was rejected [by committee]. Bill passed House of Delegates ratifying the convention entered into by H[enry] Clay and B[enjamin] W[atkins] Leigh. Discusses re-apportionment.
- James Shannon, Richmond, [Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 28 December 1822., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1343)
  Outlines debate over moving seat of justice in Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia] "Doddridge conducts himself well and is decidedly the ablest man in the House."
- James Smith, Terre Haute, [Indiana], to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 2 January 1823., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1344)
  Has received letters "giving the sad tidings of your sons deths [deaths] both of them esteemed by us all...." Lists his selections of public lands. Excuses why he has not been to White River. Has built four cabins. Gives crop prices.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to E. B. Swearinger, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 9 January 1823., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1345)
  Declines making a contract for a house belonging to Swearinger and gives reasons.
- Eliza (Woods) Paull, n.p. to [Anne (Poage) Woods] near Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 12 January 1823., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1346)
  " I am very much so [feeble] as much as possible to be out of be & troubled with doleful low spirits. The Lord knows I have not had much in a mar[r]ied life but what has been pain to body and mind;" Grieves for brother. Writes about her son, Alfred.
- M[ary (Woods)] Wilson, n.p., to Ann (Poage) Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 24 January 1823., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1347)
  Asks that Silv[i]a [a slave] be sent to her.
- W[illiam] Croghan, Pittsburgh, [Pennsylvania], to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 6 February 1823., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1348)
  Gives his terms for exchange of land.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 7 February 1823., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1349)
  Encloses form of deed and an opinion. Has referred matter of slave, Sylvia, to Mary, but is fearful that if Woods can not manage her, he will be unable to. Pleased to send Washington [Wilson?] to Philadelphia for glasses. Discusses benefits sight will provide.
- Jacob Atkinson, [Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibald] Woods,[Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia], 8 February 1823., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1350)
  Excuse for not getting brick for Woods.
- John Barr, n.p., to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia, 10 February 1823., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1351)
  Is writing for John Stipp to ask Woods to stay execution for money owed Woods.